<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Godwager]]></title><description><![CDATA[Obsidian digital garden]]></description><link>http://github.com/dylang/node-rss</link><image><url>lib\media\favicon.png</url><title>Godwager</title><link></link></image><generator>Webpage HTML Export plugin for Obsidian</generator><lastBuildDate>Fri, 23 May 2025 13:53:12 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="lib\rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><pubDate>Fri, 23 May 2025 13:53:12 GMT</pubDate><ttl>60</ttl><dc:creator></dc:creator><item><title><![CDATA[Prologue Session Notes]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br><br><br>In the wheat fields stood an old man accompanied by seven yellow canaries. The party quickly recognized this was no commoner—this was Bahamut, in mortal guise.<br>
<br>Each party member was asked to place their hand over a ghostly flame and answer a single whispered question from the canaries.<br>

<br>Their responses determined whether a canary remained or flew away—a silent judgment of truth or doubt.<br>

<br>Notable moments:<br>
<br>Lennox's canary flew away, a sign his truth was either incomplete or self-deceiving.<br>

<br>Seraphine and Topip held their ground, their canaries staying with Bahamut.<br>

<br>Varyn answered in the old tongue, concealing his words from all but Seraphine.<br>

<br>Merin was absent but would later face the question: “What would you erase to save someone you loved?” His answer: joining the Black Roses.<br>

<br>As the trial ended, Bahamut blessed the party with cryptic guidance and vanished. The path forward split three ways. The party chose the center trail, into the Misted Woods.<br><br>Entering the forest, the air thickened with magical fog—conjuration magic woven into the very atmosphere.<br>
<br>All party members were forced to make Wisdom saves.<br>

<br>Those who failed suffered intense hallucinations tied to their traumas and fears.<br>

<br>Key visions:<br>
<br>Topip saw the Tree of Life, corrupted, screaming with animal faces—accusing him of cowardice and failure.<br>

<br>Seraphine stood in a ballroom of mirrors, surrounded by masks whispering doubts about her many personas and whether she had ever truly been loved.<br>

<br>Lennox, tortured by the memory of Alana, fell apart. He whispered about seeking salvation and begged Bahamut for clarity. His visions referenced fire and guilt.<br>

<br>The mist also caused psychic damage, leaving the party disoriented and emotionally raw. Combat was not yet underway, but it loomed.<br><br>As they pressed through the fog, a figure appeared—the Mistmaster, emerging like a ghost. His voice echoed through the trees:<br>
“Come out to play.”<br>The session ended with initiative being rolled. The party stood in scattered formation, battered and unnerved, as shadows moved within the mist.<br><br><br><br>The session opened mid-combat against the Mistmaster and his Mist Stalkers, shrouded in thick magical fog. The party was scattered and fighting blind, but still pressed the assault. Early actions included:<br>
<br>Topip activated Halo of Spores and took heavy damage while maneuvering through the battlefield.<br>

<br>Lennox landed a critical hit but was soon overwhelmed, pulled to the ground, and restrained by Stalkers, screaming out the name Alana.<br>

<br>Seraphine hit the Mistmaster with a unique radiant cantrip, revealing he was vulnerable to radiant damage and disrupting his incorporeal form.<br>

<br>Varyn received a magical missive mid-fight: if he unequipped his staff for the rest of combat, a patron would immortalize him in the Halls of Triumph. He accepted and switched to his wand.<br>

<br>Topip cast Awaken on a nearby tree, animating it into a sentient, huge creature named Thumper. Thumper joined the fight with slam attacks and became a central figure on the battlefield.<br>

<br>Merin tried to clear the mist with Gust, but it had limited effect. Instead, they unleashed Magic Missile and helped pin down the weakened Mistmaster.<br>

<br>Varyn unleashed a fifth-level Fireball, sculpted to avoid allies. The explosion instantly killed two Mist Stalkers and severely wounded the Mistmaster and others. His body turned to ash, dropping two strange wrist shackles.<br>

<br>The fog began to lighten—still present, but no longer overwhelming.<br>

<br>The remaining Mist Stalkers were brutally finished off, including one being curb-stomped into the mist by Topip.<br>

<br><br>
<br>
Merin's missive revealed his greatest regret: joining the Black Roses to save someone he loved.

<br>
Lennox's breakdown continued, haunted by Alana and a mysterious fiery memory.<br>


<br>
The party recognized that these magical missives were incentives sent by powerful figures watching the Crucible—similar to gifts from sponsors in The Hunger Games.

<br><br><br>The Crucible Deepens<br>With the Mistmaster defeated and the conjured fog lifting, the party emerged into the calm of the Misted Woods. The atmosphere, once suffocating and cruel, now revealed a winding forest path—and in the distance, the outline of a forgotten town.<br><br>As they reached the forest’s edge, the land opened into cultivated fields of grain and cabbage—but something was wrong.<br>
<br>Varyn discovered the crops were hundreds of years old, yet unnaturally preserved.<br>

<br>Topip’s Druidcraft failed to influence the plant life, confirming the natural cycle was interrupted.<br>

<br>Everything felt frozen in time, held by some unknown ancient magic. Despite appearing ready for harvest, nothing grew or decayed.
<br><br>The players arrived at a seaside town made of mismatched architecture—elven fountains, dwarven homes, and human taverns, arranged in senseless proximity.<br>
<br>Signs in multiple languages flickered between dialects, including extinct ones.<br>

<br>Varyn and Topip deduced that not only the goods—but the entire town—was displaced in time.<br>

<br>Seraphine, bathing in a fountain of unnaturally warm water, heard music from a nearby tavern—a melody from an old elvish folklore song, ever-shifting and never repeating.<br>

<br><br><br>Inside the tavern, Seraphine took the stage and matched the evolving tune. As she played:<br>
<br>The party recognized the song as one once without lyrics—music from before words were ever added.<br>

<br>The party deduced: this entire town is a fragmented echo, stitched together from different eras and cultures, frozen in magical stasis.<br>

<br><br><br>At the town's center, they found a sealed cathedral with a rotating puzzle door. Its outer rings bore symbols of the Seven Ascendant Gods.<br>
<br>The group deciphered it to be a moral alignment lock, requiring the gods to be placed on a spectrum from good to evil.<br>

<br>Seraphine heard a voice in Draconic whisper: “Speak the name of secrets.”<br>

<br>She confronted Lennox, who lied about not understanding. After coaxing, he whispered a secret name—shared only between him and his lost lover, Alana Stormtail—into the ear-shaped sigil.<br>

<br>The door rumbled open, revealing a chamber of five thrones, each holding a colored goblet. Five glowing missives appeared—one for each player.<br><br><br>Each player received a personal missive, tied to a colored crystal and a powerful incentive:<br>
<br>Topip (Green): From Queen Finestra—destroy the Thorn Sovereign within the Crucible. Reward: Armor of Nature’s Favor, sacred to the Church of Rolf.<br>

<br>Seraphine (Blue): From Admiral Calasvarn—kill the Sea Tyrant. Reward: Access to the ancient magical archives, forbidden to mortals.<br>

<br>Varyn (White-Gold): From the Silver Regency—bury Dawnsever, a walking judgment blade. Reward: A governorship in Camorr.<br>

<br>Lennox (Red): From King Durk—contain the Ashbound Legion. Reward: Control over the Crucible’s boiling heart.<br>

<br>Merin (Black): From Cardinal Rowan—eradicate the Pale Dead in the Outer Crypts. Reward: Unknown.<br>

<br>There is only one pedestal—only one missive can be enacted.]]></description><link>session-notes\prologue.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Session Notes/Prologue.md</guid><pubDate>Fri, 23 May 2025 13:38:24 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>